# Ian De Bie

18102 San Gabriel Ave, Cerritos, CA 90703

Phone: 714.273.8994 • Email: ian@debie.us • Profiles:



# **Software Engineer**

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Mine is a unique situation. After many years in a stable career as an Accounting Manager, discovered my true passion is in programming. Took a chance and went back to school, and I have graduated with my BS in Computer Science. Looking for an opportunity as a Software Engineer. Dedicated worker, proven quick learner, and problem solver who is eager to contribute to the company's overall growth.

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**, December 2019

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, Utah

• Excellence Award - For exemplary work in the Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

#### COURSEWORK

- Calculus I
- Software Engineering
- Computer Architecture
- Software Quality Assurance
- Structured Query Language
- Discrete Mathematics I & II
- Web Development Foundation

- Scripting and Programming Found. & Appl.
- Data Management Foundation & Application
- Software I & II Advanced Java Concepts
- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence
- Data Structures and Algorithms, I & II
- Network and Security Foundation
- Operating Systems for Programmers

#### SKILLS



Python

Javascript

C++

PHP

SQL

HTML

SCSS

### **PROJECTS**

The projects listed below have screenshots available on my website <a href="https://ian.debie.us">https://ian.debie.us</a>. In addition, there are many more projects located in my Github repositories.

Appointment schedule app - built with Java | JavaFX | MySQL | SceneBuilder

Belle Moda dashboard built with PHP | Javascript | Laravel | Heroku Postgres

Prediction model built with Python | Javascript | Django | Heroku Postgres

Finance dashboard built with Python | Javascript | Flask | IEX API | SQLite3

Ravenous search built with React.js | Node.js | Yelp API

Visual programming sandbox built with Scratch @Scratch.MIT.edu

Cryptocurrency price retrieval built with Python | SQLite3 | CoinAPI.io API

### CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071, (10/28/2019) CompTIA Project+, (5/2/2019) CIW Site Development Associate, (2/4/2019) Axelos ITIL Foundation Cert, (10/18/2019)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Ingram Micro, Inc •** Irvine, CA (November 2011 – April 2019)

Accounting Manager (July 2015 – April 2019)

- Promoted by demonstrating core competencies and vast knowledge of company operations impacting our department
- Managed over \$3 billion in receivables per year for special pricing programs
- Used Python to create automation scripts to retrieve online reports
- Received recognition for creating various Excel templates using VBA
- Responsible for solving daily escalations from internal and external customers
- Worked extensively with SQL developers designing in-house application

Senior Accountant (August 2013 – June 2015)

Promoted after being recognized for personally maintaining \$0 aging over 90 days on over \$500 million in special pricing program receivables annually
Accountant II (November 2011 – July 2013)

- Established and cultivated relationships with our vendors driving timely resolution of outstanding receivables
- Utilized VBA and SQL to improve process efficiencies

## **Insight** • Tempe, AZ (January 2009 – October 2011)

Senior Analyst (April 2010 – October 2011)

- Promoted for managing the largest vendor program with lowest open aging Analyst (January 2009 March 2010)
  - Exceeded expectations for goals each year for write-off and aging metrics

## **Cashcall** • Anaheim, CA (2005 - 2008)

Production Manager (2007 - 2008)

• Promoted due to ability to motivate the team and assist customers, and had a high level of knowledge of the loan product programs

Loan Agent (2005 - 2007)

• Won multiple sales contests receiving over \$50K in bonus commissions

### Potter Roemer • Santa Ana, CA (1999 - 2005)

Accounting Manager (2003 – 2005)

- Promoted based on exemplary performance of prior duties
- Managed AP, AR, and payroll teams, Cost and Staff Accountants

### Cost Accountant (2002 - 2003)

- Promoted after demonstrating competencies in analysis and Excel
- Responsible for creating product bill of materials and physical inventory
- Prepared budget and forecast reporting in Excel

Staff Accountant (1999 - 2001)

- Prepared financial statements, sales/use tax returns, bank reconciliations
- Received recognition for reconciling over 12 months of unreconciled accounts

### Fisher Service Company • Paramount, CA (1996 - 1999)

Payroll Administrator (1998 - 1999)

- Promoted due to mastery of AP position by being efficient and accurate Accounts Payable (1996 1998)
  - Issue payments for approved purchase orders and review AP GL entries

# Enterprise Rent-A-Car • Carson, CA (1993 - 1996)

Leasing Accountant (1995 - 1996)

- Promoted based on attention to detail in GL by catching erroneous entries Accountant I (1993 1995)
  - General Ledger analysis and reporting

### **UPS United Parcel Service** • Cerritos, CA (1992 - 1993)

Pre-loader Package Handler (1992 - 1993)

Won multiple employee awards for speed and accuracy of loading trucks